Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 81.
And this exercise, we are going to implement the deck and Java, so how to create a deck data structure
in Java, we will create a new Java class called DAC.
So consider yourself and suppose that you are a new Java developer at Oracle and Dec is not being invented
and you are reinventing the wheel.
So how to make the class deck, how to make that these things, this data structure works together.
I want from you to go back to the lectures and where and understand that concepts and see and work with
me.
Step by step, like inserting after a year, inserting add from the it from the air and build it from
front.
And we check if it is empty, is full and so on, and we will test it later.
OK?
So I want from you to understand and wait and go with me like a professional coder.
So I will make a static start static final or I don't make static.
I make it in the constructor, so I end Max.
I will make it as max equal to or 100 I was size equal to.
And we will define it to their in their constructor entry into front.
Since we need since we are applying the deck and the deck is a cue double ended the cue and we use their
array in order as a base structure for this data structure and we used the M2 front and in rear.
OK.
So these are the data that we have used and this is that we are going to use in this data structure.
I will make this data structure constructor and I will pass the size.
So when we create a deck, I will use the array and the past 30 meters size as the array into the maximum
size.
OK, now I will assign the front equal to minus one and the rear equal to minus one.
And this size equal to size.
OK.
We are assigning it.
Now let's start making that methods.
So first of all, we will start by checking if it is rear, as is full.
OK, so Boolean Boolean is a full method and we start by checking return the result of checking this
Boolean expression in front, front, equal, front, equal to zero.
And then remember, here I use the three year equal equal to size minus one.
Then that then return the result of this comparison with different equal equal to rear rear plus one.
OK.
So this is how we check for that a full or not.
So this is a Boolean expression and this is a Boolean expression.
The result between them, if a true or true, it will return true, true or false, false and true,
false and false.
These are their possibilities.
So this would be return.
The returning value of these Boolean expression would be the result and the checking if it is full or
not.
Again, I will make is empty.
Boolean is empty and the method we will check into the front equal to one.
So from I told you in the lecture that we always check if this empty or not by checking and and seeing
the position of that front.
OK, now I will create a method called Insert Front, OK, Insert France, and it took into the perimeter
the key that we are going to insert at the beginning of the queue.
So if it is full, then don't make don't make anything.
So system.
It is full and just print for me.
System that out that the print and the overflow overflow there is an overflow here in the queue.
OK, and I need from the system to deter, OK?
Otherwise, we will start checking if we are adding at the front equal equal minus one, then the to
equal to zero and rear equal to zero.
OK, so here we are, reassigning them and we are we enclosing them at zero.
Else if there is another case, if the front here, the front equal equal to zero, then what we do,
we are going to make front equal to size minus one.
OK.
Otherwise, the else would make that front equal.
Two front front minus one.
OK.
Last thing I need to make is to assign them as they at index aren't equal to that key again.
What I have done here in searching at the front we are checking for this fall.
Don't make anything return.
If it is the front equal minus one, it is the first element.
Then at the front equal to zero and rear equal to zero.
If front equal, equal to zero, then front equal to size minus one.
Reset the front is a size minus one.
Put it to the last index and otherwise, if there is the front, just move it to minus one.
And all of these cases just put Array F of the index front equal to that key.
Just get the key and answer it at the right index front.
OK.
And starting at three, here it is the same thing, but we are using that array at index the front so
void insert every year.
This year it took into the perimeter that key that we are going to insert and we started checking it
the same way.
If it is full, then we are going to print overflow if it is equal to minus one.
If wrong, here we need also to check the front because the front is the indication, if it is, if
it has elements or not.
Now that thing that will make that difference else.
If this condition really equal equal size minus one, then not we.
We will do every year equal to zero and else what we are going to make it here equal the equal to the
year plus one.
OK.
This is the truth about making that essay at inserting at.
So at the end, we need in all of this previous cases, if conditions just we are moving that higher
index by assigning a rate at Index three equal to their case.
So here we use that key and move the key that hierarchy and we assign it later on that index.
OK.
So we are moving that here.
Here we are checking if it is full, don't make anything.
We move that year, according to the situation.
And then we assign that rate at index rate to the a key.
No, we need to make a method that deletes it from the front.
So again, void delete front.
This method we are going to make if it is empty, we check if it is empty.
So we are not going to delete anything against them that out, that print l n du is.
Empty.
OK.
Return otherwise, the deck has only one element.
So deck has only one element.
So what to do if grant equal equal to three years, then what to do front equal to minus one and rear
rear equal minus one else if the year ends if.
The front equal equal to the size minus one.
Then what to do?
We make grant equal to zero.
OK.
This is how we check.
No.
The last thing otherwise else, if it contains more than one, then franked equal to front plus one.
OK, this is how we check how we delete it from an element from the front.
Now let's check and delete an element from that area.
So the same way?
Void delete earlier at any and at an index because we are not good.
They care about the index.
We make it without 30 meters.
So we are going to f f is empty.
Checking the game system the out door to print l an empty deck, OK and return.
Otherwise, if front equal, equal to the rear, then what to do?
We are going to make France equal to minus one and as rere re initialized that here also by minus one.
OK.
Else, if we are going to make the air equal equal to zero and
three year equal to size minus one?
OK.
As the last situation is checking that the LS.
We are going.
We have many elements and we are going to initialize the rear equal minus one.
We are removing one from the rear and to delete it.
OK.
We are just making that here and moving the rear here because we are deleting from the area.
There is another methods that we are going to make like get to front, get the front end, get from
this.
If it is empty, if it is empty, then return minus one return minus one.
Otherwise, it will return the array at index slot and next front.
Because very simple, we are getting that element at the front and the index from now the same way we
are going to make get rear.
So here we have.
If it is empty or rear less than zero, then return minus one.
Otherwise, it will return at the at index every year.
OK.
This is how we make that implementation of the deck.
Now let's test this.
This program and this implementation.
So public static void, main string args and we start by creating an instance from the deck that we
have created here.
So deck deck
equal to new deck and image four elements inside at a size equal to four.
So deck dart insert Rudy year I will insert the 12 deck duct insert rear 12 14.
No.
Get we can get the elements we can get like that, the insert feront 13.
We can like deck, the delete front can delete from it or delete earlier and so on.
OK, so this is how we make the deck.
This is this is not where I would run this.
OK, nothing will happen because we didn't make anything to print out that dick insertion, deletion
or anything.
So this is the deck implementation you can continue making, making this like printing all of these
elements by making the print method and so on.
So I am waiting for your uploads, your source codes and your comments below for printing or playing
with this, these codes.
So we have finished the queue data structure, and let's move to that three.